Donovan Nguyen

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Highly motivated software engineer with strong skills in both front-end and back-end technologies with a focus on the MERN stack. With a background in biology, being able to collaborate within a team has been a focal point for me, whether it be in the laboratory or with other engineers making impactful applications. I look to bring my skills to a tech company to further advance my career and experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at 100 Devs, Los Angeles, CA

January 2022 — Present

- Collaborated with a team of developers to build modern and responsive web applications using best practices.
- Built semantically structured full stack web applications.
- Applied agile methodologies like SCRUM for project management.

Recent Projects:

Simple BTS Calculator (React.js App) – A simple React application that allows the user to determine the tip amount based on the percentage or the tip percentage based on the amount. Able to determine how much is split between multiple people either equally or by what was ordered by the user specifically.

Appointy (Fullstack Web App) – An application that allows users to login and create appointments to use as reminders for an individual's upcoming appointments. Able to place a date and time for each appointment as well as adding and removing appointments.

Other Projects: Ultima Fitness 360 website page, Los Angeles StarGazers Society APOD Web App with NASA API integration, On-demand background color changer for Partnered Twitch streamer, and many more

Full Stack Web Developer | CA

January 2022 — Present

- Freelance web developer for small and medium sized businesses.
- Provide content creation, copy, and graphic design services.
- Full life cycle web management.

Clinical Laboratory Assistant | Irvine, CA

July 2019 — May 2020

- Setup software programs for engineers running prototypes for glucose readings
- Perform glucose readings using the Piccolo blood analyzer
- Assist nurses in the process of placing an IV on patients
- Run controls to determine the accuracy and validity of machines and equipment
- · Assisted in setting up devices to allow for patients to perform the glucose study
- Perform preventative maintenance on lab equipment

CONTACT

(714) 837-0357

github.com/donovanlnguyen

linkedin.com/in/donovanlnguven

@donovanInguven

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

Javascript

React.js

Express.js

Node.js

MongoDB

SQL

OOP

Web Accessibility

EDUCATION

University of

California Fullerton

2011 - 2017

Major: Biology